{"tossups": [{"question": "In one battle in this year, Emory Upton used innovative assault column tactics to storm the Mule Shoe salient. In this year, an unsuccessful assault followed the detonation of underground explosives by Ambrose Burnside\u2019s men in the Battle of the Crater. The Battle of Spotsylvania Court House occurred in this year, as did the Battle of Yellow Tavern, in which J.E.B. Stuart died. The Siege of Petersburg began in this year that saw the Battle of the Wilderness. Sherman\u2019s March to the Sea took place in, for ten points, what year in which Lincoln was re-elected?", "answer": "<b> 1864</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One character in this novel is threatened with disinheritance after refusing John Brooke\u2019s marriage proposal. While caring for the Hummel family, a musician in this novel dies of scarlet fever. A boy living next door to this novel\u2019s protagonists marries the youngest of them after she returns from Europe; that boy is \u201cLaurie\u201d Laurence. This novel begins with its protagonists preparing for Christmas while their father serves in the Union Army. The series begun by this novel end by focusing on Fritz Bhaer\u2019s wife in <em>Jo\u2019s Boys</em>. For ten points, name this novel about the March sisters written by Louisa May Alcott.", "answer": "<b> Little Women</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "The USS<em> Charrette</em> was given to this country\u2019s navy and renamed the<em> Velos</em>, but its crew mutinied while docked at Fiumicino. Children were forcibly evacuated from communist controlled areas of this country and into camps run by Queen Frederica of Hanover. This country was ruled by the \u201cRegime of the Colonels,\u201d and the Enosis movement sought to unite Cyprus with this country. For ten points, name this Balkan country whose capital is Athens.", "answer": "<b> Greece</b> or (<b>Hellenic Republic</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One member of this group depicted his lover Hanna Fuchs-Robettin in his<em> Lyric Suite</em>, and another was accidentally killed by an American soldier shortly near the end of World War II. The founder of this group wrote a piece in which the narrator recalls living in the sewers of the title ghetto,<em> A Survivor</em> <em>From Warsaw</em>. This group developed a compositional technique that replaced traditional harmony with tone rows. Anton von Webern and Alban Berg were students in, for ten points, what early 20th century avant-garde \u201cschool\u201d led by Arnold Schoenberg in an Austrian city?", "answer": "<b> Second Viennese</b> School (accept<b> Second Vienna</b> School", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "[Note: description acceptable] This event was inspired by its performer\u2019s time at a Magdalene Laundry. A week after this event, Joe Pesci said that he would have \u201cgrabbed\u201d this event\u2019s performer \u201cby her eyebrows.\u201d It occurred during a live broadcast of a rendition of Bob Marley\u2019s \u201cWar\u201d and encouraged viewers to \u201cfight the real enemy.\u201d In its aftermath, the religious groups protested this event by using steamrollers to destroy records of songs like \u201cNothing Compares 2 U.\u201d For ten points, name this 1992 incident in which an Irish singer desecrated an image of a religious leader on Saturday Night Live.", "answer": "Sinead<b> O\u2019Connor rip</b>ping up a<b> picture of the Pope</b> John Paul II (accept synonyms for\u201cripping\u201d and \u201cpicture\u201d; prompt on partial answers that do not include person, action, and specific item)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This lake\u2019s Mumbo Island is home to an eco-friendly resort. After a failed attempt to build a mission on Cape Maclear on this lake, one was successfully established at Livingstonia, named for the first European to discover this lake. This lake is home to over 500 species of fish that are divided into either the Mbuna or Peacock groups, the cichlids. For ten points, name this Rift Valley lake that shares its name with a nearby country with capital at Lilongwe.", "answer": "Lake<b> Malawi</b> (or accept Lake<b> Nyasa</b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "After an October 2014 incident in this city, a Burger King surveillance video was supposedly erased before police reviewers were able to view it; in that incident, Jason Van Dyke was the only one of at least nine of this city\u2019s officers to fire his weapon at a 17-year-old who had fallen after one shot. A year after that incident, after police video had been released, this city\u2019s police Superintendent, Garry McCarthy, resigned, and Anita Alvarez was denied re-election as Cook County State\u2019s Attorney. For ten points, name this American city where Laquan McDonald was killed.", "answer": "<b> Chicago</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "The Spa Conference was held in response to poor coal deliveries required by this policy. This policy was nullified at the Lausanne Conference, which caused a de jure reversion to the Young Plan. Etienne Mantoux argued that this policy was justified in response to one scholar\u2019s claim that this policy would lead to a \u201cCarthaginian Peace.\u201d Herbert Hoover issued a one-year moratorium on this policy, for which the Dawes Plan had attempted to find a solution for. For ten points, name this series of payments that were forced onto a defeated Central Power nation after World War I.", "answer": "<b> German reparation</b> payments (accept<b> War Guilt</b>; accept descriptions of<b> money that Germany owed</b> after World War I)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Phrenologists noticed that bones of people from this civilization apparently exhibited Negroid facial features and argued that this civilization was visited by African traders, though less so in inland sites in the Tuxtla [toosh-t\u2019lah] mountains. Archaeological sites of this civilization, like El Manati and San Lorenzo, show minor evidence of child sacrifice, collections of jade masks, and an \u201celongated man\u201d style of figurine. For ten points, name this Mesoamerican civilization, claimed by Matthew Stirling to be the earliest, best known for its giant stone heads.", "answer": "<b> Olmec</b> civilization", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "According to Aristotle, this man bought all the olive oil presses in his city after predicting a good olive harvest. This philosopher\u2019s students, including Anaximander and Anaximenes, belonged to a school of thought named after his hometown. That school of thought attempted to explain phenomena scientifically instead of through divine action. For ten points, name this pre-Socratic philosopher from Miletus who believed that the \u201cfirst principle\u201d of matter was water.", "answer": "<b> Thales</b> [thay-lees] of Miletus", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "This author wrote a poem about figures such as Hypermnestra, Medea, and Cleopatra in a work that essentially introduced iambic pentameter to his language. This author of<em> The Legend of Good Women</em> commemorated the death of Blanche of Lancaster, the wife of John of Gaunt, in his<em> The Book of the</em> <em>Duchess</em>. In one of his stories, Arcite and Palamon fight for the love of Emily, while in another, Alisoun describes how a rapist learns that what women want is to control their husbands. For ten points, name this author of \u201cThe Knight\u2019s Tale\u201d and \u201cThe Wife of Bath\u2019s Tale,\u201d two of his<em> Canterbury Tales</em>.", "answer": "Geoffrey<b> Chaucer</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In 1622, John Brooke aboard the<em> Tryall</em> sighted Point Cloates on this island in 1622; the<em> Tryall</em> later became the first shipwreck in this island\u2019s waters, near the Montebello Islands. One explorer suggested this island\u2019s Kurnell Peninsula as a settlement site, but the first settlers to try it gave up after a week and moved to Port Jackson. Arthur Philip led 11 ships in the \u201cFirst Fleet\u201d to this island in 1787. James Cook landed at Botany Bay on the southeast shore of, for ten points, what Southern hemisphere island continent?", "answer": "<b> Australia</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "John Farmer exposed Billy Hutchinson\u2019s lies about being at this event. During this event, an ACARS message was sent reading \u201cPlz confirm all is normal.\u201d Thomas Burnett ended a phone call during this event with \u201cDon\u2019t worry, we\u2019re going to do something.\u201d This event concluded with Todd Beamer calling\u201cAre you guys ready? Okay. Let\u2019s roll!\u201d as recorded on a black box. Ziad Jarrah led hijackers on, for ten points, which part of the 9/11 terrorist attacks that ended in a field in Pennsylvania?", "answer": "the hijacking of United<b> Flight 93</b> (prompt on September 11th terrorist attacks before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "19th century immigrants from this nation formed Turner Societies to bring to the U.S. a craze for gymnastics from their home country. Discrimination against Americans of this ethnicity led to Chicago\u2019s Lager Beer Riot of 1855. One immigrant from this nation was Hayes\u2019 Secretary of the Interior and also the first U.S. Senator born in this nation; that refugee from the March Revolution was named Carl Schurz. For ten points, name this ethnicity of immigrants who introduced to our country such customs as Christmas trees, hamburgers, and hot dogs.", "answer": "<b> German</b>-Americans", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Following Rosecrans\u2019 defeat at Chickamauga, Grant drive Bragg out of Tennessee at this Union battle.", "answer": "<b> Chattanooga</b> Campaign (or Battle of<b> Chattanooga</b>) <b></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>On the death of this man, the Richmond</b><em><b> Enquirer</b></em><b> wrote \u201c[this man] was one of those patriots who fill a vast space in the nation\u2019s eye.\u201d As Speaker of the House in 1805, he became a leading figure of the Quids. Albert Gallatin wrote a bill that this man amended</b> <b>to (+)</b> <b>expire with the end of the Congressional session, killing it. Despite his personal</b> <b>opposition, this man names a bill that gave the President the power to (*)</b> suspend trade with Britain and France. For ten points, name this early 19th century North Carolina politician who names two important foreign policy bills.", "answer": "Nathaniel<b> Macon</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This phrase names a speech by Lord Palmerston that claimed all British subjects \u201cshall feel confident that the watchful eye and strong arm of England will protect him against injustice and wrong.\u201d in response to the Don Pacifico affair. It was first used by Cicero as the prosecuting lawyer against Gaius (+) Verres, and was used by Saul of Tarsus to demand a fair trial in the Book of Acts. This phrase was called \u201cthe (*)</b> proudest boast\u201d \u201ctwo thousand years ago\u201d by John F. Kennedy, who said that the modern day equivalent of this phrase was \u201cIch bin ein Berliner.\u201d For ten points, give this Latin phrase that translates to \u201cI am a Roman citizen.\u201d", "answer": "<b> civis romanus sum</b> (phonetic, or as [hee-wees romanus soom] from kids who know their classical Latin; prompt on English translations that approximate \u201cI am a Roman citizen\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This author continued Thucydides\u2019</b><em><b> History of the Peloponnesian War</b></em><b> in his</b><em><b> Hellenica</b></em><b>. Like Aristotle, this man wrote a well-regarded work discussing the constitution of the Spartans. This author\u2019s comrades were victorious at the Battle of (+) Cunaxa, though their commander was killed, and they cry out \u201cThalassa, Thalassa!\u201d or \u201cThe Sea, the Sea!\u201d after reaching the (*) </b> Black Sea. Despite its title, only the first chapter of this author\u2019s best known work describes a journey inland to join Cyrus the Younger. For ten points, name this Greek who wrote about the Ten Thousand in his<em> Anabasis</em>.", "answer": "<b> Xenophon</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>One member of this family is last seen repeatedly shouting \u201cIt\u2019s a lie!\u201d to a \u201cpitchfork senator.\u201d Another member of this family buys a five cent glass of beer using a hundred dollar bill and is given ninety five cents back. That character is sent to prison and becomes a thief alongside Jack Duane, then an agent of the corrupt (+) Mike Scully. The patriarch of this family loses his son, Antanas, when he drowns in the muddy street. That patriarch of this family is introduced at the beginning of the book as he marries (*)</b> Ona Lukoszaite at a bar in Packingtown. For ten points, name this family of Lithuanian immigrants whose patriarch Jurgis is the main character of Upton Sinclair\u2019s<em> The Jungle</em>.", "answer": "<b> Rudkus</b> (accept Antanas<b> Rudkus</b>, Jurgis<b> Rudkus</b>, or Ona<b> Rudkus</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "<b>After the second conviction of a member of this group, a nearby band played</b><em><b> There\u2019ll </b><b>be a Hot Time in the Old Town Tonight</b></em><b>. R.R. Bridges\u2019 testimony expressed extreme doubt about the supposed crimes of this group. A.E. Hawkins declared a mistrial for one member</b> <b>of this group, (+)</b> <b>Roy Wright, after the jury couldn\u2019t decide on a sentence. This group\u2019s</b> <b>convictions were overturned by the Supreme Court due to faulty (*)</b> procedures, including the use of a 100% white jury. For ten points, name this group of nine black youths whose case, in which they were convicted of raping two women on a train, went to the Supreme Court as<em> Powell v. Alabama</em>.", "answer": "<b> Scottsboro Boys</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The bones of one bishop of this city were \u201crediscovered\u201d in a column by Vitale Faliero after the cathedral in which they were housed was destroyed in a fire. That saint\u2019s body was hidden in a crate of rotting pork and cabbages to smuggle them past port customs in that saint\u2019s (+) translation from this city. Another saint from this city won a debate against 50 pagan scholars before Maxentius put her to death on a spiked (*)</b> wheel. For ten points, name this Egyptian city, home to St. Mark the Evangelist and St. Catherine, which once also held an important lighthouse and library.", "answer": "<b> Alexandria</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Salginatobel is a concrete arch bridge in this country designed by Robert Maillart.</b> <b>This country is currently dismantling a system of thousands of demolition points</b> <b>throughout its national bridges and roads to defend against invasion. Christian</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Menn has designed numerous bridges in this country, largely inspired by his</b> <b>Menn has designed numerous bridges in this country, largely inspired by his</b> <b>upbringing in this country\u2019s (*)</b> <b>upbringing in this country\u2019s (*)</b> canton of Graubunden. For ten points, name this country where many of its best engineers were educated at ETH Zurich.", "answer": "<b> Switzerland</b> BONUS:<em> Seven Pillars of Wisdom</em> is an autobiographical work detailing part of what British soldier\u2019s career abroad? ANSWER:<b> Lawrence</b> of Arabia (or Thomas Edward<b> Lawrence</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}